Abdulla Abbadi, Software Developer

BRONX, UNITED STATES · abdulla.m.abbadi@gmail.com · (347) 281-1982

LinkedIn

LINKS

Portfolio

PROFILE

GitHub

Junior Software Developer, knowledgeable in all stages of web development. Competent in both back-end and front-end development. Experienced in the following programming languages and frameworks Python, JavaScript, Java, Django, Flask, and React. Willing to learn new technologies and cooperate to build and maintain working software.

Python

SKILLS

EXPERIENCE

Django React

React Front-End Developer, Self Project

HTML & CSS

Jan 2022 — Apr 2022, New York, NY

Bootstrap

• Developed my portfolio website using Node.js and React.js.

JavaScript

• Personal website to show future employers my experience, skills, and education.

Agile Scrum

• Link: https://abbadi-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Git

Python Full Stack Developer, Khaf Al-omniat

Mar 2021 — Jan 2022, Aden, Yemen

Flask

• Developed a full-stack E-commerce app for a crafts shop.

OOP

• Designed use cases to accommodate slow internet connection and offline services.

• The app helped increase sales by 25%.

Java

• Link: https://www.caveofwishs.com/

MySQL

Python Full Stack Developer, SUNY at Buffalo

Linux

Aug 2020 — Dec 2020, Buffalo, NY

· Collaborated on school project implementing Agile scrum methodology.

Problem Solving

• Developed the project's back-end user functionalities, and also contributed to the profile page front-end.

Flexibility and Adaptability

• Link: https://github.com/CSE-Courses/course-project-a3-massive-muscles

Leadership and Teamwork

Full Stack Developer, SUNY at Buffalo

Good work ethic

• Developed real-time blog

• Video link: https://youtu.be/VgEjhzVwAKs

University at Buffalo, Bachelors of Science

Creativity

• Project Link: https://github.com/wafflez180/CSE312-Web-Apps-Project

LANGUAGES

EDUCATION

Jan 2020 — May 2020, Buffalo

English

Feb 2014 — Dec 2020, Buffalo, NY

Arabic

• Learned most of the skills required to work in the field of Software Development.

• Learned the mathematical theory of computation, such as algorithms, and data structures.

• Learned the best practices in software development, such as security, and ethics.